Guide to the Hans Bethe papers, ca. 1931-1995
Bethe, Hans papers,
- Series I. Research
  - Subseries IV. Articles by others
    - Gerry, Basic paper, begin. 23-4-91, 1991 (Box 5, Folder 7)
    - Woosley, Langer, Weaver, binaries, 1992 (Box 5, Folder 8)
    - K- Condensation, 1993 (Box 5, Folder 9)
    - Gerry, Neutron Star Binaries, 1993, 1994 (Box 5, Folder 10)
    - Woosley-Baron, (n.d.) (Box 5, Folder 11)
    - Lamb, quantum physics, 1986-1999 (Box 5, Folder 12)
    - Misc articles by others, part 1, 1993-1999 (Box 5, Folder 13)
    - Misc articles by others, part 2, 1989-1996 (Box 5, Folder 14)
    - Astrophysics papers, 1992-1999 (Box 5, Folder 15)
    - Astrophysics papers II, 1992-1998 (Box 5, Folder 16)
    - Misc Astrophysics and Quantum Mechanics articles, 1994-1998 (Box 5, Folder 17)
    - Articles on astrophysics, quantum mechanics, etc., 1995-1998 (Box 5, Folder 18)
    - Physical Review Letters, 1936-1967 (Box 5, Folder 19)
    - History of Physics, 1987, 1989 (Box 5, Folder 20)
    - EMC effect, (n.d.) (Box 5, Folder 21)
    - Gerry, main paper, Correspondence, 1990, 1991 (Box 5, Folder 22)
    - QCD, Quark-Gluon papers, 1991 (Box 5, Folder 23)
    - Wilczek QCD, 1993 (Box 5, Folder 24)
    - 1987A, Pierre, Bolometric Corrections, (n.d.) (Box 5, Folder 25)
    - Misc. SN 1987A, (n.d.) (Box 5, Folder 26)
    - Reprints, astrophysics, 1978-1991 (Box 5, Folder 27)
    - Wilson et al, stellar collapse, 1982 (Box 5, Folder 28)
    - Neutrinos and stellar collapse, 1983, 1987 (Box 5, Folder 29)
    - Hadron to Quark Transition Reprints, 1983-1990 (Box 5, Folder 30)
    - Nomoto et al, supernovae, 1984, 1988 (Box 5, Folder 31)
    - Baron thesis, supernovae, 1985 (Box 5, Folder 32)
    - Coop, supernovae, 1985 (Box 5, Folder 33)
    - Neutrino Flow (Coop), 1985-1987 (Box 5, Folder 34)
    - Accretion, 1985-1991 (Box 5, Folder 35)
    - Burenn, Bludman etc, core collapse and SN shock, 1986, 1987 (Box 5, Folder 36)
    - Misc. astrophysics, 1986-1994 (Box 5, Folder 37)
    - SN 87A, Neutrinos, Observation and Calculations, 1987 (Box 5, Folder 38)
    - SN 1987A, Woosley II, ind. Pre-SN, 1987, 1988 (Box 5, Folder 39)
    - 1987A, light curve, Woosley, 1987-1989 (Box 5, Folder 40)
    - SN 1987A, Nomoto et al, 1987-1990 (Box 5, Folder 41)
    - SN 1987A, 1987-1991 (Box 6, Folder 1)
    - Wilson Refs., 1988, 1989 (Box 6, Folder 2)
    - Large Scale Astronomy, 1989 (Box 6, Folder 3)
    - G. West, QCD, 1989, 1991 (Box 6, Folder 4)
    - Misc. supernova, 1989-1991 (Box 6, Folder 5)
    - QCD, 1991 (Box 6, Folder 6)
    - Early Nuclear Abundances, 1991, 1992 (Box 6, Folder 7)
    - QCD, 1992 (Box 6, Folder 8)
    - Jim Wilson, type II supernovae, 1993 (Box 6, Folder 9)
    - Richtmyer-Meshkov et al, instability, 1993 (Box 6, Folder 10)
    - Office, articles, (n.d.) (Box 6, Folder 11)
    - Misc Articles, 1986-1991 (Box 6, Folder 12)
    - Cosmology Papers, 1990 (Box 6, Folder 13)
    - Brown-Rho., 1994 (Box 6, Folder 14)
    - Misc Articles, 1994-1996 (Box 6, Folder 15)
    - Scientific publications (general), 1995-1999 (Box 6, Folder 16)
    - Stars, 1997-1999 (Box 6, Folder 17)
    - Misc Articles, 1998-1999 (Box 6, Folder 18)
    - Nuclear Tables, Fowler et al, 1968-1983 (Box 6, Folder 19)
    - Fowler et al, thermonuclear reaction rates, 1994-1995 (Box 6, Folder 20)
    - Dark Matter, 1988 (Box 6, Folder 21)
    - Mass limit for Black Holes, Maeder, 1992 (Box 6, Folder 22)
    - Binaries, Iben, Nomoto, 1993 (Box 6, Folder 23)
    - Cosmology, 1993-1994 (Box 6, Folder 24)
    - Janka, supernovae, 1994-1995 (Box 6, Folder 25)
    - Low Hubble, 1995 (Box 6, Folder 26)
    - Binary evolution, (n.d.) (Box 6, Folder 27)
    - Charts: Fermi-Dirac Functions, (n.d.) (Box 6, Folder 28)
    - Chevalier, Woosley-Weaver, (n.d.) (Box 6, Folder 29)
    - Stellar dynamics, (n.d.) (Box 6, Folder 30)
    - Nuclear Reaction Rates, 1975-1984 (Box 6, Folder 31)
    - Weak Interaction Rates, Fuller et al, 1980, 1982 (Box 6, Folder 32)
    - Woosley, Summary Articles, 1980-1986 (Box 6, Folder 33)
    - Neutrinos: see-saw model, 1980-1987 (Box 6, Folder 34)
    - Woosley and Weaver, supernovae, 1981 (Box 6, Folder 35)
    - Burrows, astrophysics, 1984 (Box 6, Folder 36)
    - Helfand, astrophysics, 1984 (Box 6, Folder 37)
    - Gerry Brown, neutron stars and supernovae, 1985-1997 (Box 6, Folder 38)
    - Haxton, neutrino oscillations, 1986 (Box 6, Folder 39)
    - Reaction rates, 1986 (Box 6, Folder 40)
    - Neutrino: Non-adiabatic, Pizzochero, 1987 (Box 6, Folder 41)
    - Woosley letters, 1988 (Box 6, Folder 42)
    - Woosley, Arnett, 1987A, 1988, 1989 (Box 6, Folder 43)
    - Woosley papers, 1988-1989 (Box 6, Folder 44)
    - Scientific American, SN 1987A, 1989 (Box 6, Folder 45)
    - Heuvel, binaries, 1989, 1996 (Box 6, Folder 46)
    - Dimotakis' Lane-Emden, 1991 (Box 6, Folder 47)
    - Basic Info, Lane-Emden, (n.d.) (Box 6, Folder 48)
    - Supernova Woosley, Explosive Nucleosynthesis, 1991 (Box 6, Folder 49)
    - Bludman, solar neutrino, 1991-1992 (Box 6, Folder 50)
    - SN 1987A, black hole, 1992 (Box 7, Folder 1)
    - 17-keV neutrino, 1992 (Box 7, Folder 2)
    - Massive stars, black holes, 1993-1996 (Box 7, Folder 3)
    - Initial Mass Function, 1995 (Box 7, Folder 4)
    - Dimotakis, turbulent-flow, (n.d.) (Box 7, Folder 5)
    - Edward Streeter, Decoding the Sun, (n.d.) (Box 7, Folder 6)
    - Jim Langer, Earthquakes, (n.d.) (Box 7, Folder 7)
    - Lamb, Curie, Fermi, (n.d.) (Box 7, Folder 8)
    - Red Atom by Paul R. Josephson, a Manuscript, (n.d.) (Box 7, Folder 9)
    - Snyder, Physics Careers, (n.d.) (Box 7, Folder 10)
    - The Sommerfeld School, (n.d.) (Box 7, Folder 11)
    - Jagdish Mehra, misc., 1952-2004 (Box 7, Folder 12)
    - Atomic Physics, 1969-1972 (Box 7, Folder 13)
    - John Ray Dunning, 1969, 1975 (Box 7, Folder 14)
    - General Interest Articles, 1973, 1969 (Box 7, Folder 15)
    - Science and Press, 1980 (Box 7, Folder 16)
    - Theory on Relativity, 1996 (Box 7, Folder 17)
    - Misc: Julian Sackmann and Wigner recollections, 1999 (Box 7, Folder 18)
    - Montreal Lab, Nuclear Reactor Theory, 2000 (Box 7, Folder 19)
    - Fermi's QED, 2001 (Box 7, Folder 20)
    - Negele, muonic atoms, 1960-1969 (Box 7, Folder 21)
    - Nuclear matter, 1969, 1970 (Box 7, Folder 22)
    - Pi-nucleus, Papers by Others (1971, 1972) 1 of 2, 1971, 1972 (Box 7, Folder 23)
    - Pi-nucleus, Papers by Others (1971, 1972) 2 of 2, 1971, 1972 (Box 7, Folder 24)
    - Strutinsky, Heavy Nuclei, 1972 (Box 7, Folder 25)
    - Explosive-Electric Dynamos, Logmire, (n.d.) (Box 7, Folder 26)
    - Physics Today, 1963, 1963 (Box 7, Folder 27)
    - Cosmic Rays, 1938 (Box 53, Folder 1)
    - Reports on Progress in Physics, 1971, 1972 (Box 53, Folder 2)
    - Quantum Mechanics, 1973 (Box 53, Folder 3)
    - Nucleon-Nucleon Potentials, 1975 (Box 53, Folder 4)
    - Waves, 1951-1975 (Box 53, Folder 5)
    - Sudbury Neutrino Observatory, 1985 (Box 53, Folder 6)
    - Neutrinos, German Article, 1987 (Box 53, Folder 7)
    - Neutrino Oscillations, Mikheyev and Smirnov, (n.d.) (Box 53, Folder 8)
    - Double-Beta-Decay, 1986 (Box 53, Folder 9)
    - Flavons, Yukawa Matrices, 2003 (Box 53, Folder 10)
    - Unknown Notes Regarding Higgs, 1 of 2, (n.d.) (Box 53, Folder 11)
    - Unknown Notes Regarding Higgs, 2 of 2, (n.d.) (Box 53, Folder 12)
    - Neutrinos, Italian presentation, (n.d.) (Box 53, Folder 13)
    - Statistical Mechanics, Schiff and Baroody, 1945 (Box 53, Folder 14)
    - Birmingham Conference on Nuc. Physics, 1953 (Box 53, Folder 15)
    - MIT Conference on Photonuclear Physics, 1953 (Box 53, Folder 16)
    - Design Concepts for Borex, 1988 (Box 53, Folder 17)
    - Conference on Absolute Beta Counting, 1950 (Box 53, Folder 18)
    - Deuteron Problem, Code for Automatic Electronic Computer, 1953 (Box 53, Folder 19)
    - Ted Quirk, 2000 (Box 115, Folder 10)
    - Sohar, 1998 (Box 115, Folder 11)
    - Thorne, 1998 (Box 115, Folder 12)
    - Pistoe on Missile Shield, 2002 (Box 115, Folder 13)
    - C.J. Wasserburg, 1998-2003 (Box 115, Folder 14-15)
    - Dieter Hoffman (Box 115, Folder 16)
    - Robert Bacher, 2004 (Box 115, Folder 17)
    - Eskreis-Winkler Paper, 2004 (Box 115, Folder 18)
    - Kenneth Williams clippings and photos, 1982 (Box 115, Folder 19)
    - Poggendorf, 1993 (Box 115, Folder 20)
    - David Hawkins, 1999 (Box 115, Folder 21)
    - Willis Lamb (Box 115, Folder 22)
    - Bahcall, Thorne, 1999 (Box 115, Folder 23)
    - Yuri Orlov, 1999 (Box 115, Folder 24)
    - Ewald Deutches Museum essay material, 2010 (Box 115, Folder 25)
    - Brown and Lee (Box 117, Folder 6)
  - Subseries V. Talks
    Notes, material and overhead projections for talks and lectures Bethe gave, mostly outside of the context of Cornell lecture courses. Includes material for the series of lectures Bethe gave in 1997 at Kendall of Ithaca about quantum physics, and other public talks. For lectures and talks at Cornell, please see the Cornell series.
    - Physics of Dense Matter Symposium, Boulder, 1971, 1972 (Box 17, Folder 46)
    - NSF Visit, Spring 68. (1968), 1968 (Box 17, Folder 47)
    - Talk to Science Writers, May 68, 1968 (Box 17, Folder 48)
    - Pohl talk, 1974 (Box 17, Folder 49)
    - Energy Talks, 1975 (Box 17, Folder 50)
    - Hans Bethe [Kendal lectures], 1999 (Box 17, Folder 51)
    - Quantum Theory, Copy 5, 1999 (Box 17, Folder 52)
    - Qu. Th. Vugraphs, Duplicates of I and II, 1999 (Box 17, Folder 53)
    - Photos for star talk, (n.d.) (Box 17, Folder 54)
    - Stars, Citadel, 1968 (Box 17, Folder 55)
    - Pittsburgh Stars 1980?, Tubingen 1987, 1980, 1987 (Box 17, Folder 56)
    - Star Talk, Mich., 1988 (Box 17, Folder 57)
    - Talks given on ABM in '68, calcs., 1968 (Box 17, Folder 58)
    - Life in Physics, 1997 (Box 17, Folder 59)
    - 30 years of physics at Cornell, 1965 (Box 17, Folder 60)
    - War College, 1968, 1968 (Box 17, Folder 61)
    - Kendal Seminar, 1997 (Box 17, Folder 62)
    - Bethe, Vancouver talk, 1973 (Box 17, Folder 63)
    - Stellar Energy, Harvard, Cornell, Copies of Vugraphs, (n.d.) (Box 17, Folder 64)
    - Bethe, electromagnetism theory, (n.d.) (Box 17, Folder 65)
    - Oskar Klein lecture, (n.d.) (Box 17, Folder 66)
    - Solar Neutrinos, LA talk 1991, Providence, Cornell '95, Argonne '96, 1991-1996 (Box 17, Folder 67)
    - Livermore Visit, 1985 and 1986, 1985, 1986 (Box 17, Folder 68)
    - Kendal Lyceum lectures, 1998 (Box 17, Folder 69)
    - Quantum Th. Copy 2, The Kendal Lectures, 1999 (Box 17, Folder 70)
    - Hans Bethe, The Interior of Stars, 1998 (Box 18, Folder 1)
    - Buffalo Talk, Fermi and H-bomb, (n.d.) (Box 18, Folder 2)
    - U.N. Talk, Atomic Weapons, (n.d.) (Box 18, Folder 3)
    - Misc. Talk, Posters/notes, 1989-1997 (Box 18, Folder 4)
    - Bethe, Marshak Symposium, 1977 (Box 53, Folder 47)
- Series II. Policy
  This series includes Bethe’s documents on issues of public policy, particularly regarding science and technology. This series includes material related to policy in the broadest sense, including his arguments on the ethical and social responsibilities of scientists and his work on presidential advisory committee. It contains his work on arms control, including nuclear testing bans and non-proliferation, and his advocacy related to energy policy. Documents range from correspondence, to relevant articles and papers, to copies of speeches and talks, to material from advocacy organizations of which Bethe was a member.
  - Subseries I. General
    - Committee on Nuclear Science, 1954 (Box 28, Folder 53)
    - Seismology Report, 1959 (Box 28, Folder 54)
    - Sloan Program. Science education., 1959 (Box 28, Folder 55)
    - Science Education. Talk given to N.Y. State Citizens Comm. for the Public Schools. Rochester 1958, 1958 (Box 28, Folder 56)
    - Schools 11/11/60, 1960 (Box 28, Folder 57)
    - Physical Society New York. Feb 4, 1961, 1961 (Box 28, Folder 58)
    - Social Responsibilities, 1967 (Box 28, Folder 59)
    - The Scientist and Society, Feb 26, 1968, 1968 (Box 28, Folder 60)
    - The Social Responsibilities of Scientists and Engineers, 1968 (Box 28, Folder 61)
    - Guest Lecture: Science, technology and policy, 1970 (Box 28, Folder 62)
    - New York Employment Meeting, 1971 (Box 28, Folder 63)
    - Williamsburg, 1971 (Box 28, Folder 64)
    - Science Education talk. Early 1958, 1958 (Box 28, Folder 65)
    - Ethical Responsibilities, 1983 (Box 28, Folder 66)
    - Science Advisory Group, 1975 (Box 28, Folder 67)
    - Chernobyl and other issues, 1990's (Box 28, Folder 68)
    - Misc. Policy, 1985 (Box 28, Folder 69)
    - Moynihan, 1991-1997 (Box 28, Folder 70)
    - Sheinbaum, 1993 (Box 28, Folder 71)
    - Pittsburgh Lectures, 1981 (Box 28, Folder 72)
    - Hippocratic Oath for Scientists, 1987 (Box 29, Folder 1)
    - Scientists in India, 1964 (Box 29, Folder 2)
    - Science Politics and Funding, 1974-1982 (Box 29, Folder 3)
    - Oppenheimer Memorial Lecture, 1975 (Box 29, Folder 4)
    - Science Court Colloq., Sep. '76, 1976 (Box 29, Folder 5)
    - New Perspective Quarterly, 1997 (Box 29, Folder 6)
    - Policies: FAS and Democratic Senatorial Campaign Committee, 1998 (Box 29, Folder 7)
    - TV 'Spot', 1980 (Box 29, Folder 8)
    - Economics - Kahn, 1981 (Box 29, Folder 9)
    - Allen V. Austin Case, 1953 (Box 29, Folder 10)
    - Killian, Advisory Committee, 1958 (Box 29, Folder 11)
    - Engineering Manpower Commission, 1960 (Box 29, Folder 12)
    - IAN, Institute of All Nations, 1975, 1976 (Box 29, Folder 13)
    - International Conference on the Unity of the Sciences, 1980 (Box 29, Folder 14)
    - Population Per Capita Income, 1980 (Box 29, Folder 15)
    - Economics, 1981 (Box 29, Folder 16)
    - Physics Teachers, 1993 (Box 29, Folder 17)
    - Nuclear-Physics Panel, Nuclear Science, 1971 (Box 56, Folder 27)
    - Interview on American Character, Bethe, 1962 (Box 56, Folder 28)
    - Nuclear Physics Manpower, 1975 (Box 56, Folder 29)
    - AEC Special Safeguards Study, 1974 (Box 56, Folder 30)
    - Hiroshima and Nagasaki Cancers, 1981 (Box 56, Folder 31)
    - Biological Effects of Radiation, 1974-1979 (Box 56, Folder 32)
    - Oppenheimer Case, Security, 1954 (Box 57, Folder 1)
    - US Security, (n.d.) (Box 57, Folder 2)
    - NAS Annual Report, (n.d.) (Box 57, Folder 3)
    - Niels Bohr, 'The Unity of Human Knowledge', 1960 (Box 57, Folder 4)
    - ACEN News, 1956, 1957 (Box 57, Folder 5)
  - Subseries II. Energy
    Contains Bethe’s policy work on energy. (For his research and consulting related to nuclear energy, please see the consulting series). It consists mostly of advocacy for nuclear energy as a solution to U.S. energy needs, but also includes material on nuclear waste disposal, the energy crisis of the 1970’s, alternative energies and cold fusion. It also includes records pertaining to advocacy organizations of which Bethe was a member, most significantly Americans for Energy Independence (known originally as AEI and later as AFEI) and Scientists for Enlightenment on Nuclear Sources of Energy (SENSE). (Bethe served as president of SENSE). Includes talks, papers and op-eds, testimony, and correspondence.
    - Minor Talks, (n.d.) (Box 18, Folder 5)
    - Conservation, co-generation, 1973-1980 (Box 18, Folder 6)
    - AIF File [publications], 1975-1980 (Box 18, Folder 7)
    - Bernard Cohen, 1976 (Box 18, Folder 8)
    - Meinel [Energy], 1976 (Box 18, Folder 9)
    - Energy. Conf. in Florida Nov. 77, 1977 (Box 18, Folder 10)
    - Vital Statistics: Population, 1977 (Box 18, Folder 11)
    - Nuclear Power. Minor papers, Letters, etc., 1978-1981 (Box 18, Folder 12)
    - Environmentalism, 1979 (Box 18, Folder 13)
    - Princeton--Einstein, 1979 (Box 18, Folder 14)
    - Cal Tech, 1979-1980 (Box 18, Folder 15)
    - Energy Talks and Press Reports, 1979-1981 (Box 18, Folder 16)
    - Energy conference, 1980 (Box 18, Folder 17)
    - SE2 Symposia, 1980-1981, 1980-1981 (Box 18, Folder 18)
    - Radon, 1981 (Box 18, Folder 19)
    - Energy Conservation, 1974 (Box 18, Folder 20)
    - Bulletin, 1975 (Box 18, Folder 21)
    - Public attitudes, nuclear power, 1975 (Box 18, Folder 22)
    - Salzburg. Contributions of others, 1977 (Box 18, Folder 23)
    - Churches, 1978 (Box 18, Folder 24)
    - Nuclear Power: General, 1976-1980 (Box 18, Folder 25)
    - Gold's Natural Gas Theory, 1979-1981 (Box 18, Folder 26)
    - Press Relations, 1981 (Box 18, Folder 27)
    - B. Lewis, energy, 1968-1974 (Box 18, Folder 28)
    - Energy Correspondence, 1974, 1975 (Box 18, Folder 29)
    - Niagara Falls, San Diego, 1975 (Box 18, Folder 30)
    - TV Master Copy, 1975 (Box 18, Folder 31)
    - TV Sept. '75, figs. for film, 1975 (Box 18, Folder 32)
    - Danz Lectures, Manuscripts, 1976 (Box 18, Folder 33)
    - Lovins debate, 1976, 1977 (Box 18, Folder 34)
    - Lovins Publications, 1976-1978 (Box 18, Folder 35)
    - Lovins Letters, 1977, 1978 (Box 18, Folder 36)
    - Commoner - Komanoff, 1977 (Box 18, Folder 37)
    - Numbers on Energy, 1979 (Box 18, Folder 38)
    - Reactors: draft, (n.d.) (Box 18, Folder 39)
    - Proposed book, unpublished; Sci Am Nucl. Power, Main Copy, 1981 (Box 18, Folder 40)
    - Cold Fusion, 1989-1990 (Box 18, Folder 41)
    - Solar Energy, 1977 (Box 18, Folder 42)
    - Nuclear Power: Special Designs, 1978 (Box 18, Folder 43)
    - DOE on magnetohydrodynamics, 1979 (Box 19, Folder 1)
    - Energy for AIP, (n.d.) (Box 19, Folder 2)
    - Radkovsky--Feldhamer, (n.d.) (Box 19, Folder 3)
    - Candu, 1975 (Box 19, Folder 4)
    - Ford Foundation, 1975 (Box 19, Folder 5)
    - Solar Energy Assessments, 1975-1980 (Box 19, Folder 6)
    - Safeguards (Sandia), 1976 (Box 19, Folder 7)
    - Solar LASL, 1976-1977 (Box 19, Folder 8)
    - Energy correspondence, 1976-1979 (Box 19, Folder 9)
    - Tables for Energy Talks, 1977-1980 (Box 19, Folder 10)
    - Reactors and safety (Albrecht), 1978-1979 (Box 19, Folder 11)
    - Decentralization, 1979 (Box 19, Folder 12)
    - Lewis: Economics of nuclear power, 1979 (Box 19, Folder 13)
    - Energy Urbana, 1979-1980 (Box 19, Folder 14)
    - AIP Handbook, 1980 (Box 19, Folder 15)
    - Energy Info 1980, 1980 (Box 19, Folder 16)
    - Lovins 11/6/80, 1980 (Box 19, Folder 17)
    - Solar Satellite, 1980 (Box 19, Folder 18)
    - Sweden: Waste Disposal, 1980 (Box 19, Folder 19)
    - Energy Policy, 1980-1982 (Box 19, Folder 20)
    - Energy Notes, 1981 (Box 19, Folder 21)
    - Sept. 81 talks, Energy, 1981 (Box 19, Folder 22)
    - Fusion Breeder, 1981-1984 (Box 19, Folder 23)
    - Energy Info, outline, 1982 (Box 19, Folder 24)
    - Energy, Sep. 82. Talks Harvard, 1982 (Box 19, Folder 25)
    - WHCU 16-3-83, 1983 (Box 19, Folder 26)
    - Fusion Breeder, 1985 (Box 19, Folder 27)
    - Fusion, General, 1985 (Box 19, Folder 28)
    - Publications: Nuclear Energy, 1986-1990 (Box 19, Folder 29)
    - BWR Oscillations, 1988 (Box 19, Folder 30)
    - Carson. Natural Radioactivity Bkgd, 1988 (Box 19, Folder 31)
    - Nat. Geographic Film on Fusion, 1988 (Box 19, Folder 32)
    - Breeders and Reactors (1974-1983), 1990 (Box 19, Folder 33)
    - Effects of Chernobyl, 1990 (Box 19, Folder 34)
    - Fast reactors, 1990 (Box 19, Folder 35)
    - Pigford: Actinide Burning, Waste Disposal, 1990 (Box 19, Folder 36)
    - Accelerator Waste Transmutation, 1991 (Box 19, Folder 37)
    - Actinide Recycle Program: Report, 1991 (Box 19, Folder 38)
    - Chernobyl Consequences, 1991 (Box 19, Folder 39)
    - ITER, 1991 (Box 19, Folder 40)
    - Cold Fusion, 1991-1992 (Box 19, Folder 41)
    - DOE, 1994-1995 (Box 19, Folder 42)
    - Energy: Special Countries, 1975-1977 (Box 19, Folder 43)
    - Fusion, 1975-1979 (Box 19, Folder 44)
    - Lovins, energy, 1976-1980 (Box 19, Folder 45)
    - Asbury et al, Electric Heating, 1976-1981 (Box 19, Folder 46)
    - Economics, 1977, 1979 (Box 19, Folder 47)
    - Nuclear Energy, other people's writings, 1977-1979 (Box 19, Folder 48)
    - Waste Disposal, 1978-1979 (Box 19, Folder 49)
    - Synthetic Fuels, Energy, 1979 (Box 19, Folder 50)
    - Nuclear Power: IEA, 1980 (Box 19, Folder 51)
    - American Nuclear Society, 1980, 1981 (Box 19, Folder 52)
    - Excess Pu, 1994 (Box 19, Folder 53)
    - Hans Bethe - Prophet der Energie, 1988 (Box 19, Folder 54)
    - Wilson - Cheap Nuclear Electricity, 1998 (Box 19, Folder 55)
    - Availability of Nuclear Plants. Comey and rebuttal, 1975 (Box 20, Folder 1)
    - Economics of nucl. Power, 1975 (Box 20, Folder 2)
    - Solar Energy, 1976 (Box 20, Folder 3)
    - Nat. Council of Churches, 1976-1977 (Box 20, Folder 4)
    - Anti-Nuclear Articles and Refutations, 1978 (Box 20, Folder 5)
    - Energy General, (n.d.) (Box 20, Folder 6)
    - material and notes on reactors, (n.d.) (Box 20, Folder 7)
    - Energy and energy talks, 1971-1975 (Box 20, Folder 8)
    - More Nuclear Waste, 1972-1978 (Box 20, Folder 9)
    - Waste Disposal, 1973-1974 (Box 20, Folder 10)
    - City College and Older Versions, 1974 (Box 20, Folder 11)
    - City College Lecture, 1974 (Box 20, Folder 12)
    - Copies of Energy Talk, 1974 (Box 20, Folder 13)
    - Energy Talk: Reserve Copies, 1974 (Box 20, Folder 14)
    - Tables; Energy Talk, 1974 (Box 20, Folder 15)
    - Pu toxicity ind. Dr. Cobb, 1974-1976 (Box 20, Folder 16)
    - Energy I. Reserve Copies, 1975 (Box 20, Folder 17)
    - Joint Committee, 1975 (Box 20, Folder 18)
    - Notes on Energy Talks, 1975 (Box 20, Folder 19)
    - Wingspread, 1975 (Box 20, Folder 20)
    - Calif. Legislat, 1975-1976 (Box 20, Folder 21)
    - California Hearing, Oct 75, and related material, 1975-1976 (Box 20, Folder 22)
    - Gofman, 1975-1976 (Box 20, Folder 23)
    - Biological Effects, 1975-1976 (Box 20, Folder 24)
    - Health and Nuclear Energy, 1975-1976 (Box 20, Folder 25)
    - Plutonium Bio-Hazards (H.Div.), 1975-1976 (Box 20, Folder 26)
    - Waste Disposal. Blomeke, Claiborne and Gera, 1975-1978 (Box 20, Folder 27)
    - Argonne Meeting, Oct. '76, 1976 (Box 20, Folder 28)
    - Fast Reactor Safety, Jan. '76, 1976 (Box 20, Folder 29)
    - Senate Committee, Reactor Exports, 1976 (Box 20, Folder 30)
    - General on Nuclear Material, Safeguards, 1976-1977 (Box 20, Folder 31)
    - Nuclear safety reports, 1977 (Box 20, Folder 32)
    - Ted Taylor, 1977-1978 (Box 20, Folder 33)
    - Sep. 18 Debate, 1979 (Box 20, Folder 34)
    - Nuclear Waste, 1979-1980 (Box 20, Folder 35)
    - Nuclear Energy in Industry, ANL, 1980 (Box 20, Folder 36)
    - Stevens Energy Journal, 1980 (Box 21, Folder 1)
    - Opposing Statements, 1974-1976 (Box 21, Folder 2)
    - Negative Statements on Energy, 1975 (Box 21, Folder 3)
    - Statement on Nuclear Energy, Jan. 1975, 1975 (Box 21, Folder 4)
    - Nuclear Power and Energy Resources, 1975-1991 (Box 21, Folder 5)
    - Coal, 1972-1973 (Box 21, Folder 6)
    - Energy Crisis, 1972-1973 (Box 21, Folder 7)
    - Safety Debate, 1972-1973 (Box 21, Folder 8)
    - Fusion Foundation, 1972-1977 (Box 21, Folder 9)
    - Energy Talk Old, 1973 (Box 21, Folder 10)
    - Pugwash on Energy, 1973 (Box 21, Folder 11)
    - Energy Crisis articles, 1973-1974 (Box 21, Folder 12)
    - Reactor Safety, 1974 (Box 21, Folder 13)
    - Superconductors. Brookhaven, 1974 (Box 21, Folder 14)
    - Aspen Center, 1975 (Box 21, Folder 15)
    - Aspen Institute Talk, 1975 (Box 21, Folder 16)
    - Siegel: Nuclear issues booklet, 1975 (Box 21, Folder 17)
    - Academy Forum, 1975-1976 (Box 21, Folder 18)
    - Fusion Energy Found, 1975-1976 (Box 21, Folder 19)
    - DC SPTL, Philadelphia (Q Div.), 1976 (Box 21, Folder 20)
    - Fusion-Fission, 1976 (Box 21, Folder 21)
    - Oil, 1976 (Box 21, Folder 22)
    - Texas Energy Center, 1976 (Box 21, Folder 23)
    - Tom Jones: alternative energy (Club of Rome), 1976 (Box 21, Folder 24)
    - We almost lost Detroit, 1976 (Box 21, Folder 25)
    - Tom Gold: Methane, 1978-1979 (Box 21, Folder 26)
    - My papers on Energy, 1973-1975 (Box 21, Folder 27)